ILGWU Auditing Department Publications 5780/192 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Auditing Department Publications
1935-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/192 PUBS
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Publications (documents).
This collection contains publications of the Auditing Department, including statements of receipts and disbursements (1935-1960), census reports (1952-1984), and financial reports of general funds (1961-1994).
6323437
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Z. Owen, August 18, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
The ILGWU Auditing Department was organized in October 1914, under the direction of B.M. Rabinovitch. It was charged with auditing the local unions, joint boards, district councils and departments, and the general office of the ILGWU. The Department presented these reports to the General Executive Board and to the ILGWU's International conventions.
Scope and Contents
Beginning in 1935, the ILGWU published annual financial reports that accounted for the International office's receipts and disbursements, as well as those of affiliate local unions, joint boards, district councils and departments. These reports detailed the disbursements from the local unions, joint boards, and district councils and departments to the international office (dues stamps and assessments), administrative expenses (salaries for office staff, office rent, printing, stationary, postage, telephone and telegraph, janitor, cleaning, light, dues to other organizations, miscellaneous expenses), organization expenses (salaries for managers, business agents, adjusters, organizing expenses, elections, strike relief, legal fees, loss of time, collection of dues, education, hall rent, advertisements, etc.), and donations and relief (such as the Anti-Nazi drive, labor causes, charitable, community, or cultural organizations). Local unions also paid towards the operation of the joint boards of which they were member organizations.
Reporting was again altered in 1958. Before then, whether in the convention report or an annual report, the union's financial information was presented in tables that listed local unions by number, followed by joint boards, district council and departments, and finally, the international office. After 1958, these presented the same information by area (e.g., Northeast Department Area, Southwest Area, etc.), and concluded with a listing of joint boards, district councils and department and their affiliated locals.
The Census Reports in this collection provide general information about the membership, presenting the annual statistical schedule of dues stamps purchased from the international office and a comparison of dues-paying members with actual membership census.
Prior to 1935, the ILGWU published information about its membership and finances along with reports presented at the international conventions. These reports provided membership numbers, broken down by male or female and also by number of members working by week or by piece. They also detailed the amounts local unions paid out and collected. In addition, some of these reports included brief summaries of strikes (e.g., won, lost, pending, number involved, cost, and gains), injunctions, and general conditions in the trade. Such additional financial and membership information may be found in financial and statistical reports in 5780/193 PUBS and 5780/121 PUBS.
Taken together, the reports in this collection provide a statistical overview of the membership and finances of the ILGWU. Researchers interested in the more detailed information on these aspects of the union, or on the membership and finances of specific local unions, joint boards, and district councils and departments, should consult finding aids to those affiliates' records.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/079: ILGWU Local 62 Managers' Correspondence 5780/102 P: ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/192 MF: ILGWU Auditing Department Records
Women's clothing industry--United States; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States; Textile workers--United States; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Auditing Dept
6323437
- Statement of Receipts and Disbursements, 1935-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Statement of Receipts and Disbursements, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Auditing Department. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Statement of Receipts and Disbursements, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Auditing Department. 2 copies each 1959 and 1960. Item is in English.
- Census Report, 1952-1984; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Census Report, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Auditing Department. 2 copies each 1976 and 1980. Item is in English.
- Financial Report: General Funds, 1961-1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Financial Report: General Funds, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Auditing Department. 2 copies each 1961, 1963, and 1965. Item is in English.
- Financial Report: General Funds, 1966-1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Financial Report: General Funds, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Auditing Department. 2 copies each, except only one 1969. Item is in English.
- Financial Report: General Funds, 1976-1982; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Financial Report: General Funds, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Auditing Department. 2 copies each, except three for 1982. Item is in English.
- Financial Report: General Funds, 1983-1994; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Financial Report: General Funds, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)